Guide to the African American history marketing and promotional posters, 1967-1984 and undated RL.11386
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
African American history marketing and promotional posters
1967-1984 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture
RL.11386
1.0 Linear Feet
Consists of approximately 50 posters the bulk of which consist of corporate promotions depicting notable African Americans or significant moments in African American history and culture. Posters include biographical sketches of African American writers, scientists, professional athletes, soldiers, civil rights workers and celebrity entertainers. Participating companies include Anheuser-Busch (Budweiser), Army National Guard, CIBA-GEIGY, Columbia Artists Management, Federal Home Loan Bank, Honeywell, Nabisco and Pepsi. Also included in the collection are a number of promotional posters produced by and for the NAACP that address the organization's campaigns to reduce poverty, school dropouts and voter registration, as well as calls to join the NAACP. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture and the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The African American history marketing and promotional posters were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2017.
Collection Overview
Consists of approximately 50 posters the bulk of which consist of corporate promotions depicting notable African Americans or significant moments in African American history and culture. Posters include biographical sketches of African American writers, scientists, professional athletes, soldiers, civil rights workers and celebrity entertainers. Participating companies include Anheuser-Busch (Budweiser), Army National Guard, CIBA-GEIGY, Columbia Artists Management, Federal Home Loan Bank, Honeywell, Nabisco and Pepsi. Also included in the collection are a number of promotional posters produced by and for the NAACP that address the organization's campaigns to reduce poverty, school dropouts and voter registration, as well as calls to join the NAACP. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture and the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
African and African American History; African Americans -- History; Posters, American -- 20th century; Posters; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; Anheuser-Busch, inc.; CIBA-GEIGY Corporation; Pepsi-Cola Company; Honeywell Inc; Nabisco Brands, Inc.
- Anheuser-Busch (Budweiser) presents Great Kings of Africa series, 1981 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Features: Affonso I; Askia Mohammed Toure; Mansa Kankan Mussa; Shaka Zulu; Menelek II; Hannibal; Akhenaton; Taharqa/Tirharkah
- Ciba-Geigy: Exceptional Black Scientists series, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  Features: Lloyd N. Ferguson; Augustus A. White III; Samuel L. Kountz; David Blackwell; Jennie R. Patrick; LaSalle D. Leffall Jr.; Reatha Clark King; Walter E. Massey
- Columbia Artists at Carnegie Hall posters, Undated (Box 1)
  Features: Shirley Verrett; Leontyne Price
- Crisis 60th Anniversary Issue poster, 1970 (Box 1)
- Emergency Relief Fund, Undated (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous corporate sponsorship posters, 1975-1981 and undated (Box 1)
  Includes: Army National Guard: You Belong, featuring William H. Carney 1975; Army National Guard: Hell Fighters from Harlem 1974; Bell System: Communication in Black Culture; Coors: Heritage Series "Settlers" 1981; Honeywell: Martin Luther King Jr. "The ultimate measure of a man..." 1980; Nabisco: Famous Black American Writers
- NAACP recruitment and promotion posters, 1967 and undated (Box 1)
  Includes: Back to School/Stay in School Program; Civil Rights is for Everybody Regardless of Color Join NAACP; "In There" Join Work in the NAACP featuring Bob Gibson approximately 1967; Keep the Idea of Freedom Alive Join NAACP featuring Mrs. Medgar W. Evers; People is What the NAACP is About; What's Your Bag Brother Helpin' or Hurtin'
- Pepsi-Cola: The Black Presence series, Undated (Box 1)
  Features: Paul Robeson; Harriet Tubman; John Henry; Jackie Robinson; Charlie Christian; Alexander Dumas; Garrett A. Morgan
- Political and voter registration posters, Undated (Box 1)
  Includes: Charles Evers Senate campaign; 18 Year Old Can Vote--Have You Registered?; Be Counted on Election Day--Register So You Can Vote; Black Is Beautiful But You Look Prettier When You Are Registered; Put Your Vote Where Your Mouth Is
- Project Rural Conference "The Time Is Now", 1979 (Box 1)
- WWRL (Sonderling Broadcasting Corporation) census maps of New York, N.Y., 1960 (Box 1)
- COMSAT "Communicate" featuring art by A. Hakim Qawiyy, Undated (Folder 1)
- Federal Home Loan Bank "Frederick Douglass Is Looking for a Job", Undated (Folder 1)
- Spirit of '76--American Brotherhood, 1974 (Folder 1)
- The Nuclear Arms Race/The Alternatives, 1983 (Folder 1)